<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> - Articles</title>
    <description>Writing things down so I don't forget. SDE at AWS. Opinions expressed are my own.</description>
    <link>
    https://dejanperetin.com</link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Why I Don't Vote</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Wolfram Mathematica is an amazing software that I love using, but the choice to use it for any meaningful application is 
difficult to justify due to its cost and licence. Presidential elections in Croatia seemed like a good excuse to fire it
up and generate some graphs. Which I did. And here is the winner of the election per administrative subdivisions: &lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/why_i_dont_vote/finalni_rezultati_po_opcinama.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 10:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://dejanperetin.com/why-i-dont-vote</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dejanperetin.com/why-i-dont-vote</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Nobody Reads Shit</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Watched an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UE-6zvdRapY&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;amp;t=391&quot;&gt;H3 podcast&lt;/a&gt; 
episode yesterday and they were commenting 
on how YouTube is announcing policy changes on a blog instead of via video. 
Comments were premised by the fact that YouTube is
a video company, but the question of who reads blogs (or anything for that matter) was raised. 
This reminded me that I have a blog of my
own. Blog that I didn’t look at for more than 5 years.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 11:28:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://dejanperetin.com/nobody-reads-shit</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dejanperetin.com/nobody-reads-shit</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>CVS merge in Eclipse</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever so often a need for merging CVS branches arises  and since the task can be a bit touchy, writing down some basic concepts seems like a good idea. So here are a few basic steps the process boils down to.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 10:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://dejanperetin.com/cvs_merge</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dejanperetin.com/cvs_merge</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Kako napraviti svoj build LZS android aplikacije</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Dobio sam nekoliko mailova od ljudi koji su pokušali sami napraviti build aplikacije prema uputama na wiki stranicama te naišli na probleme. 
Te upute su dosta stare i grube pa se bez nekog iskustva s eclipsom po 
njima niti nije mogao napraviti build. Detaljnija i korisnija uputsva su očito potrebna pa sam ih odlučio i napisati.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2013 11:33:37 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://dejanperetin.com/lzs-app-build-howto</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dejanperetin.com/lzs-app-build-howto</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>KDM i Grub stavke kod restarta</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Za ljude koji imaju više stavki na GRUB izborniku i često ih koriste. U datoteci &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/usr/share/kde4/config/kdm/kdmrc&lt;/code&gt; postoji linija koja se odnosi na &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;BootManager&lt;/code&gt; (zadnja u donjem kodu):&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 11:33:37 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://dejanperetin.com/kdm-grub-listings-hr</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dejanperetin.com/kdm-grub-listings-hr</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Android 4.2 developer options</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Nedavno sam ulovio vremena da na svoj Galaxy S mudrofon konačno stavim Android 4.2.1 i to kao &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyanogenmod.org/blog/cm-10-1-m-series-builds-have-arrived&quot;&gt;CM 10.1 M&lt;/a&gt;.Stvar radi savšeno i za sad nisam naišao na probleme u svakodnevnom korištenju. No, kad sam pokušao vidjeti kako se &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/linuxzasve/androidApp&quot;&gt;Linux za sve android app&lt;/a&gt; ponaša na novoj verziji Androida, nisam uspio uključiti debugging mod. Naime, Android 4.2 nema u &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; izborniku stavke &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Developer options&lt;/code&gt;, gdje se uključuje &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Android debugging&lt;/code&gt; opcija koja omogućava debugiranje android aplikacija direktno na uređaju koji je USB-om spojen na računalo, umjesto da se koristi emulator.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2013 10:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://dejanperetin.com/android-42-developer-options-hr</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dejanperetin.com/android-42-developer-options-hr</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Raspberry Pi - prvi dojmovi</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Raspberry Pi (&lt;em&gt;u daljnjem tekstu RPi&lt;/em&gt;) je stigao. Malo računalo u maloj kutiji.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2012 11:33:37 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://dejanperetin.com/rpi-prvi-dojmovi-hr</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dejanperetin.com/rpi-prvi-dojmovi-hr</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
